# **Trevor Farthing -** Software Developer

☆ Kirkland, WA 98034 **425.999.1328** 

https://trevorfarthing.com

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Software developer with two years of experience creating business solutions and product enhancements. Highly proficient using C#, C++, Java, and Python. Creative problem solver who works well alone or in a collaborative environment. Quick learner of new technologies. Results driven with the ability to look outside the box to find workable solutions.

### **EDUCATION**

BS Computer Science, minor Math, Cum Laude | Gonzaga University, Spokane, WA, May 2018 GPA: 3.55

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018-2020, Software Developer | C-Labs Corporation, Bellevue, WA 2016-2017 (summers), Software Development Intern | C-Labs Corporation, Bellevue, WA

- Designed, developed, and maintained plugins for **IIoT** (Industrial Internet of Things) platform.
- Investigated and helped address performance issues of **Pub-Sub** messaging system by developing scalable **Docker**-based test framework.
- Produced a new, customized way to record sensor historian data into an **InfluxDB** time-series database.
- Developed plugin utilizing **Grafana** to allow improved data visualization of sensor historians.
- Enhanced distributed storage system by implementing interface to store application data in **SQL** Server.
- Configured **Azure Kubernetes** cluster of Prometheus and Grafana pods to monitor cloud metrics.
- Created logger that extracts information from **IIS** failed request trace files and writes to system log.
- Extended and optimized local storage functionality by implementing an "append" option for JSON files.

2014-2016 Fundraising Caller | Gonzaga University Telefund, Spokane, WA

- Contacted hundreds of alumni and parents nightly to secure donations for the university.
- Contributed to fundraising over \$1 million for the university.

#### RELATED PROJECTS

- Created **Vue.js** frontend for cloud-based development environment and project management tool with senior design project team.
- Recorded, edited, mixed, and produced 8-song album over the course of a year. Proficient in Digital Audio Workstations and video editing software.
- Built personal website with CI/CD pipeline using Gulp and Github Actions deploying to AWS.
- Earned the Eagle Scout Rank with the Boy Scouts of America.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

C#

Javascript Java

 HTML/CSS Python

C++ Vue.is

SQL

Docker

Kubernetes

IIS

AWS Cloudfront

REST

npm Gulp

Git

 Swagger/OpenAPI Ableton Live

AWS S3

Final Cut Pro X